<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frontend on Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/tags/frontend/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frontend on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:49:56 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/frontend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Readable Time Intervals in Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:49:56 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</guid>
      <description>Expressing time intervals in a format that is readable by humans is an old problem that every frontend developer will eventually face. While there are plenty of solutions available (this one is my favourite), I required a function that could provide different levels of granularity in it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;human-readable&amp;rdquo; description of time.
Take, for example, a component that tells the user how long in aggregate they have been using a service. If they have been using it for a few hours, it would be appropriate to display ## hours, ## minutes, ignoring the seconds and milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Review: BrisJS - Introducing the TypeScript Compiler, Atomic Design, Scrutinising the Norm</title>
      <link>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:06:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I attended the first BrisJS meetup of the year last night. This was my first time attending a &amp;ldquo;programming language-centric&amp;rdquo; meetup, and I was surprised to find around 100 people in attendance. All presenters and the majority of the crowd looked to be in their 20&amp;rsquo;s, and while the presentations didn&amp;rsquo;t have the level of polish that I would usually expect for an event of this size, I was still able to learn a few things, and more importantly, have some interesting conversations with other developers about projects they are working on and opportunities in the market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>