<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Snippets on Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/categories/code-snippets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code Snippets on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 16:17:10 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/code-snippets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert SQL Query to CSV File Using Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 16:17:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-using-python/</guid>
      <description>This function takes an SQLAlchemy query object as it&#39;s input (SQLAlchemy is a popular Python SQL toolkit and Object Relational Mapper). It&#39;s strength lies in not needing to hard-code column names, making it scaleable and suitable to &amp;ldquo;set-and-forget&amp;rdquo;.
While developing enterprise software, every developer has surely have been faced with a client asking &amp;ldquo;how do I get the data out of the system?&amp;quot;, and after digging a bit deeper, it becomes clear they want the ability to save a snapshot of data as an Excel spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Powershell Profiles Like a Pro</title>
      <link>/post/20200210-use-powershell-profile-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 20:31:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200210-use-powershell-profile-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>If you do any software development in a Windows environment, you&#39;ll be spending enough time inside the Powershell (PS) console that it will be worth customizing the PS Profile to speed up your workflow.
The PS Profile is essentially a .ps1 script that is run whenever a new PS console is opened. Without going too deep into how a sysadmin might use it, the average developer will probably want to use it to quickly do a few basic things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Google from the Powershell Console</title>
      <link>/post/20200209-search-google-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 18:09:03 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200209-search-google-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>You may have seen people walking around with those awkwardEat; Sleep; Code; Repeat; brogrammer shirts. I don&#39;t like them - between the many other things that developing software requires, when I actually sit down to write code the workflow would more accurately be described as Code; Compile; Google Error; Repeat;.
This short post explains how the below gg.ps1 Powershell script can increase your productivity by opening a chrome browser and executing a Google search straight from the Powershell console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Deployment of a Hugo Website to Github Pages using Powershell Scripts</title>
      <link>/post/20200207-automating-deployment-hugo-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 15:12:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200207-automating-deployment-hugo-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Overview The following article describes how this blog is automatically deployed. The technology stack for this blog is:
 Source content written within the Hugo framework (a static website generator written in the Go language. Hosted by GitHub Pages, directly from this repository which contains the website build (the source code is in a separate repository). Cloudflare for cached content delivery (along with many other things).  If the technology stack for your project is completely different, this article should still provide you with:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>