<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:20:16 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Higher-Order Functional Components (HOCs) in React (with Typescript)</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-14-higher-order-components-hocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:20:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-14-higher-order-components-hocs/</guid>
      <description>Background Higher-Order Components are &amp;ldquo;functions that take a component and return a new component&amp;rdquo;, and while they are not part of the React API, &amp;ldquo;they are a pattern that emerges from React&amp;rsquo;s compositional nature&amp;rdquo; (React docs).
HOCs can be used to avoid repeated code in many scenarios such as:
 showing a loader, while waiting for data, conditionally rendering components, managing common user-interactions states, providing components with specific styles, and more generally, providing a component with any prop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS Gotchas with logical operators || and &amp;&amp;</title>
      <link>/post/20211229-javascript-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 11:39:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20211229-javascript-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>Overview Javascript&amp;rsquo;s logical OR || and logical AND &amp;amp;&amp;amp; operators are useful in contexts other than creating if, else, while etc. statements, but there are some edge cases that that I see many devs (myself included) getting caught out by.
This article explores common pitfalls, and provides recommendations for:
 using || to define values with a default fallback, and using &amp;amp;&amp;amp; to conditionally render JSX components only when required props are defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline web automation development (Python &#43; Selenium)</title>
      <link>/post/20210701-streamline-web-automation-development-python-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:47:07 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20210701-streamline-web-automation-development-python-selenium/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr When using Python to write web scraping / general automation scripts, run Python using the -i flag preserve and interact with the latest state (i.e python -i script.py).
This let&amp;rsquo;s you avoid re-running the whole script every time a change is made.
Problem When developing a bot or web scraper that operates behind a login screen, development, testing, and debugging can take longer than you might expect. The process of write code --&amp;gt; test --&amp;gt; debug --&amp;gt; repeat hits a bottleneck every time the browser starts, pages load, login details are entered, the welcome page loads, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser debugging with bookmarklets</title>
      <link>/post/20200907-browser-debugging-with-bookmarklets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 16:48:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200907-browser-debugging-with-bookmarklets/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  Bookmarklet are browser bookmarks that, instead of linking to a web page, inject custom javascript into the current page. Here are a couple of bookmarklets I use regularly - to add them to your browser simply copy the minified code directly into the URL field for a new bookmark (remember to include the javascript: prefix).  Track current mouse coordinates Use the below script to display the current mouse coordinates in the current tab title:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn touch typing using custom reading materials with Typr</title>
      <link>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:05:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Typr is a simple web-based typing tutor that lets you practice typing using your own material. It also provides live feedback on typing speed, and in the future will include detailed statistics and algorithmically-generated custom exercises.
 Create an account and use it for free here. Check out some screencasts of the UI. Check out the source code on Github.  The demo is currently hosted on a Heroku free-tier server which treats itself to a nap when there is no traffic and can take up to 30 seconds to wake up, so please be patient!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to type at 100 WPM in two weeks</title>
      <link>/post/20200823-type-at-100-wpm-in-two-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:37:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200823-type-at-100-wpm-in-two-weeks/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  It&amp;rsquo;s hard to underestimate the importance of typing. Unless you are a journalist, legal secretary, or professional writer, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t get enough practice to ever become truly fast. I built Typr and used it to simultaneously read &amp;amp; type &amp;ldquo;Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!&amp;rdquo;. Two weeks and 100,195 words later, I was maintaining between 100-110 WPM after starting out at 50 WPM. If you like reading, kill two birds with one stone by using Typr to practice typing material you would otherwise be reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 ideas to improve Clipchamp</title>
      <link>/post/20200420-idea-machine-clipchamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:21:27 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200420-idea-machine-clipchamp/</guid>
      <description>This is part of the Idea Machine, an ongoing series of short posts inspired by a James Altucher article titled Write Ten Ideas Every Day And Within Three Months You Will Have Rewired Your Brain. Read more about the project here.    Listening to instrumental beats while watching the news, lectures or other educational videos is something I have always done. It keeps my brain just busy enough to maintain consistent focus, plus I find it endlessly amusing to hear the rhythmic cadence of a good speaker lining up perfectly with a solid beat and a chunky bassline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and manage Selenium web scrapers with Auto-Scrape</title>
      <link>/post/20200224-manage-selenium-web-scrapers-with-auto-scrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 22:49:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200224-manage-selenium-web-scrapers-with-auto-scrape/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Auto-scrape let&amp;rsquo;s you focus on writing web scraping scripts, while it takes care of logging, data persistance, data presentation and data export, all through a modern browser-based UI. It can be run locally or deployed remotely.
 Here are some screencasts of the UI. Get it on Github.  Why scrape the web? Building a Selenium web scraper is almost a rite of passage for programmers starting out. Watching a computer fill out forms, click links and collect data before your eyes is not only a highly satisfying and suitably non-abstract exercise for beginners to complete - browser automation forms a foundation for frontend testing, can be used for automated research, and of course can be used to replace those expensive and unreliable humans to accomplish a wide range of business-related tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-readable time intervals in Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:49:56 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</guid>
      <description>Expressing time intervals in a format that is readable by humans is an old problem that every frontend developer will eventually face. While there are plenty of solutions available (this one is my favourite), I required a function that could provide different levels of granularity in it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;human-readable&amp;rdquo; description of time.
Take, for example, a component that tells the user how long in aggregate they have been using a service. If they have been using it for a few hours, it would be appropriate to display ## hours, ## minutes, ignoring the seconds and milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert SQL query to CSV file in Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 16:17:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-in-python/</guid>
      <description>This function takes an SQLAlchemy query object as it&amp;rsquo;s input (SQLAlchemy is a popular Python SQL toolkit and Object Relational Mapper). It&amp;rsquo;s strength lies in not needing to hard-code column names, making it scaleable and suitable to &amp;ldquo;set-and-forget&amp;rdquo;.
While developing enterprise software, every developer has surely have been faced with a client asking &amp;ldquo;how do I get the data out of the system?&amp;rdquo;, and after digging a bit deeper, it becomes clear they want the ability to save a snapshot of data as an Excel spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use powershell profiles like a pro</title>
      <link>/post/20200210-use-powershell-profile-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 20:31:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200210-use-powershell-profile-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>If you do any software development in a Windows environment, you&amp;rsquo;ll be spending enough time inside the Powershell (PS) console that it will be worth customizing the PS Profile to speed up your workflow.
The PS Profile is essentially a .ps1 script that is run whenever a new PS console is opened. Without going too deep into how a sysadmin might use it, the average developer will probably want to use it to quickly do a few basic things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Google from the powershell console</title>
      <link>/post/20200209-search-google-from-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 18:09:03 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200209-search-google-from-powershell/</guid>
      <description>You may have seen people walking around with those awkwardEat; Sleep; Code; Repeat; brogrammer shirts. I don&amp;rsquo;t like them - between the many other things that developing software requires, when I actually sit down to write code the workflow would more accurately be described as Code; Compile; Google Error; Repeat;.
This short post explains how the below gg.ps1 Powershell script can increase your productivity by opening a chrome browser and executing a Google search straight from the Powershell console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating deployment of a Hugo website to Github Pages using powershell scripts</title>
      <link>/post/20200207-automating-deployment-hugo-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 15:12:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200207-automating-deployment-hugo-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Overview The following article describes how this blog is automatically deployed. The technology stack for this blog is:
 Source content written within the Hugo framework (a static website generator written in the Go language. Hosted by GitHub Pages, directly from this repository which contains the website build (the source code is in a separate repository). Cloudflare for cached content delivery (along with many other things).  If the technology stack for your project is completely different, this article should still provide you with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event review: BrisJs - Introducing the typescript compiler; Atomic design; Scrutinising the norm</title>
      <link>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:06:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I attended the first BrisJS meetup of the year last night. This was my first time attending a &amp;ldquo;programming language-centric&amp;rdquo; meetup, and I was surprised to find around 100 people in attendance. All presenters and the majority of the crowd looked to be in their 20&amp;rsquo;s, and while the presentations didn&amp;rsquo;t have the level of polish that I would usually expect for an event of this size, I was still able to learn a few things, and more importantly, have some interesting conversations with other developers about projects they are working on and opportunities in the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event review: Collaborate at RCL</title>
      <link>/post/20200131-collaborate-at-rcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 12:31:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200131-collaborate-at-rcl/</guid>
      <description>I attended &amp;ldquo;Collaborate at RCL&amp;rdquo; last night, an event hosted by River City Labs, described as follows:
 What do you do when you have an amazing business idea, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills or resources to make it happen? Help others with their ideas, and they&amp;rsquo;ll help you with yours!
That&amp;rsquo;s the idea behind Collaborate @ RCL. Meet some great people, learn some new skills, and work on some fantastic businesses - all at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Chris. This blog is where I write about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about. It&amp;rsquo;s a place to organize my thoughts and ideas in a place where other people might be able to find some value in it.
I am a software engineer at Microsoft, have previous experience as an engineering consultant and project manager, and have used my skills in mathematics and programming to help businesses automate their engineering design and project management processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Full Name* Email* Mobile Company Message* I am a human* Fields marked with an asterisk are required.   Send   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Learn touch typing using custom reading materials with Typr    August 23, 2020   Projects    tl;dr Typr is a simple web-based typing tutor that lets you practice typing using your own material. It also provides live feedback on typing speed, and in the future will include detailed statistics and algorithmically-generated custom exercises. Create an account and use it for free here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
