<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>React on Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/tags/react/</link>
    <description>Recent content in React on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 11:39:50 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Javascript: Gotchas with logical operators || and &amp;&amp;</title>
      <link>/post/20211229-javascript-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 11:39:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20211229-javascript-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>Overview Javascript&amp;rsquo;s logical OR || and logical AND &amp;amp;&amp;amp; operators are useful in contexts other than creating if, else, while etc. statements, but there are some edge cases that that I see many devs (myself included) getting caught out by.
This article explores common pitfalls, and provides recommendations for:
 using || to define values with a default fallback, and using &amp;amp;&amp;amp; to conditionally render JSX components only when required props are defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn touch typing using custom reading materials with Typr</title>
      <link>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:05:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Typr is a simple web-based typing tutor that lets you practice typing using your own material. It also provides live feedback on typing speed, and in the future will include detailed statistics and algorithmically-generated custom exercises.
 Create an account and use it for free here. Check out some screencasts of the UI. Check out the source code on Github.  The demo is currently hosted on a Heroku free-tier server which treats itself to a nap when there is no traffic and can take up to 30 seconds to wake up, so please be patient!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
