<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:49:56 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Readable Time Intervals in Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 14:49:56 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200218-human-readable-time-intervals-python/</guid>
      <description>Expressing time intervals in a format that is readable by humans is an old problem that every frontend developer will eventually face. While there are plenty of solutions available (this one is my favourite), I required a function that could provide different levels of granularity in it&#39;s &amp;ldquo;human-readable&amp;rdquo; description of time.
Take, for example, a component that tells the user how long in aggregate they have been using a service. If they have been using it for a few hours, it would be appropriate to display ## hours, ## minutes, ignoring the seconds and milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert SQL Query to CSV File in Python</title>
      <link>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 16:17:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200217-sql-to-csv-in-python/</guid>
      <description>This function takes an SQLAlchemy query object as it&#39;s input (SQLAlchemy is a popular Python SQL toolkit and Object Relational Mapper). It&#39;s strength lies in not needing to hard-code column names, making it scaleable and suitable to &amp;ldquo;set-and-forget&amp;rdquo;.
While developing enterprise software, every developer has surely have been faced with a client asking &amp;ldquo;how do I get the data out of the system?&amp;quot;, and after digging a bit deeper, it becomes clear they want the ability to save a snapshot of data as an Excel spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>