<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Chris Palmieri</title>
    <link>/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Chris Palmieri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 16:48:39 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Debugging with Bookmarklets</title>
      <link>/post/20200907-browser-debugging-with-bookmarklets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 16:48:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200907-browser-debugging-with-bookmarklets/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  Bookmarklet are browser bookmarks that, instead of linking to a web page, inject custom javascript into the current page. Here are a couple of bookmarklets I use regularly - to add them to your browser simply copy the minified code directly into the URL field for a new bookmark (remember to include the javascript: prefix).  Track current mouse coordinates Use the below script to display the current mouse coordinates in the current tab title:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn touch typing using custom reading materials with Typr</title>
      <link>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:05:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200823-typr-typing-tutor-web-app/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Typr is a simple web-based typing tutor that lets you practice typing using your own material. It also provides live feedback on typing speed, and in the future will include detailed statistics and algorithmically-generated custom exercises.
 Create an account and use it for free here. Check out some screencasts of the UI. Check out the source code on Github.  The demo is currently hosted on a Heroku free-tier server which treats itself to a nap when there is no traffic and can take up to 30 seconds to wake up, so please be patient!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Review: BrisJS - Introducing the TypeScript Compiler, Atomic Design, Scrutinising the Norm</title>
      <link>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 09:06:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20200204-brisjs-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I attended the first BrisJS meetup of the year last night. This was my first time attending a &amp;ldquo;programming language-centric&amp;rdquo; meetup, and I was surprised to find around 100 people in attendance. All presenters and the majority of the crowd looked to be in their 20&amp;rsquo;s, and while the presentations didn&amp;rsquo;t have the level of polish that I would usually expect for an event of this size, I was still able to learn a few things, and more importantly, have some interesting conversations with other developers about projects they are working on and opportunities in the market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>